Guide to the William L. Brown, Jr. papers,1960-1990.
Brown, William L., Jr.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William L. Brown, Jr. papers, 1960-1990.
21-01-3532
William L. Brown, Jr.
13.9 cubic ft.
Galley proofs, photographs, correspondence, subject files, metal-etched blocks.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection contains galley proofs including original drawings for publications, photographs, subject files, course files, correspondence, notebooks, field books, and metal-etched blocks used in illustrations used in publications.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor Brown taught entomology and evolutionary theory in the Department of Entomology in the New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences at Cornell University from 1960 until his retirement in 1991. He worked on the reclassification of the family Formicidae, the ant. Before coming to Cornell, he worked with all of the principal museum ant collections in North and South America, Western Europe, South Africa and Australia.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection contains galley proofs including original drawings for publications, photographs, subject files, course files, correspondence, notebooks, field books, and metal-etched blocks used in illustrations used in publications.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brown, William L., Jr.
Subjects:
Entomology--Study and teaching.; Field ants
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal-Correspondence, CV, Publications
Box 1
Series II. Drawings, Galleys, Photocopies, Photographs, Scanning Electron Microscope (SEM) Shots
Boxes 1, 2
Series III. Course Information
Box 2
Series IV. Pilot Register of Zoology (PRZ)
Box 2
Series V. National Science Foundation (NSF) Grants
Box 2
Series VI. Subject Files
Boxes 3, 4
Series VII. Manuscripts, Notes, Maps, Articles, Reprints, Correspondence, Studies and Data
Box 4
Series VIII. Administrative Records, Committee Reports
Box 4
Series IX. Trips
Box 4
Series X. Karyotypes and Printing Materials
Box 5
Series XI. Notebooks
Box 6
Series XII. Oversize Galley Proofs
Boxes 7-9
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Personal-Correspondence, CV, Publications
  - Correspondence, 1961-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence-Ant-Plant, 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - CV and List of Publications (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets-Foreign (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II. Drawings, Galleys, Photocopies, Photographs, Scanning Electron Microscope (SEM) Shots
  - Ant Drawings, Various Species-I (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ant Drawings, Various Species-II (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ant Drawings, Various Species-III (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ant Drawings, Various Species-IV (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ant Wings (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bornean "Lordomyrma"-Drawings (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Centrifugal Speciation"-Figures and Proof Figures (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dacitini-Pencil Drawings-Mostly Mandibles (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Drawings for Amblyoponine Paper (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Original Drawings-Amblyoponini (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Original Drawings-Ectotonmini-Wing Prints and Negatives (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Drawings-Hypopnera (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Drawings-Illustrations Done for Insects of Australia (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Drawings-Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Drawings (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Drawings (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Drawings (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Drawings-Myrmicine Genera (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Drawings-Ponerini (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Drawings-Smithistruma (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Drawings-Various (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Figures-Colorum Colobostrum (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Figures-Dacitini, Mainlyvolsellae (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Figures-Epostruma (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Figures-Genetic Structure-Hypoponera (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Figures and Photos-Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Figures-New World-Strum. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Figures for "Punctuated Equilibrium" Paper from Academic Press Ltd. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Figures-Rhoptromyerex (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Figures-S.Sisyndata-Negatives (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Galley Proofs-Delicata (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Galley Proofs-Drawings and Figures (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Galley Proofs-Drawings and Figures (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Galley Proofs-Drawings and Figures (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Galley Proofs-Drawings and Figures (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Galley Proofs-Drawings and Figures (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Galley Proofs-Drawings and Figures (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Galley Proofs-Drawings and Figures (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Galley proofs-Drawings and Figures (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Galley Proofs-Drawings and Figures (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Galley Proofs-Drawings and Figures for Odontomechus Paper (VI A) (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Galley Proofs-Various Ant Data-Costa Rica, Indonesia (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Galley Proofs-Indomyrna (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Photocopies-Strumgundlachi-Group Figures (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Photographs of Ants (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Photographs-Ant Chromosomes (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Ants' Wings (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photographs for Taylor's Mesotrama Paper (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photographs-Ants (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Plates for Typhlomyrmecine Paper (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Plate 1-Unidentified (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Prints-Simopelta Transverse Pachy. Spp. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - SEM Photographs and Negatives-Hymenoptera Data, 1974-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - SEM Photos of Sm. Ornata and Galley Proofs (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - SEM Shots (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - SEM Shots (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - SEM Shots-Various Species (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series III. Course Information
  - Systematics Course-Bio. Sci. 470/760 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bio. Sci. 475-Course Evaluations, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bio. Sci. 477-Course Evaluations, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Chromosome Course-Steve Bloom (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Course Reports, Exams, Evaluations, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Series IV. Pilot Register of Zoology (PRZ)
  - Questionnaire-Pilot Register of Zoology-Responses, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Register of Zoology-Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pilot of Register Zoology-Cladarogenys--#33, #34, #38, #39, #40 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Pilot Register Zoology-Follow-up, 1964-1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series V. National Science Foundation (NSF) Grants
  - Ant Bibliographic NSF Grant -William L. Brown, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - NSF Grant, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - NSF Grant-Renewal Application, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - NSF Grant-GB 2175-Expenditures, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - NSF Grant-Renewal, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - NSF Grant-GB 5574X, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - NSF Grant-GB 5574X1, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - NSF Grant-Proposal #31662X, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - NSF Grant-GB #24822, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - NSF Grant, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - NSF Grant, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - NSF Grant, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - NSF Grant, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - NSF Research, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - NSF Grant Proposal, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - NSF, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - NSF Proposals, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - NSF Final Grant-1981 Trip (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - NSF--Final Project Report--#80-03722 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - NSF Proposal-"The ALL Workshop", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Series VI. Subject Files
  - "A Curious Theory" (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Alpine-Arctic Ants-Notes (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Society of Scientists (A. S. S.) Appeal and Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Anochetus (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Anochetus Cato Group (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ant Book-Inquilines (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ant Chromosomes-Data and Photos (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ants-General-Solicitation of Series for Naming "Split" Samples (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ant Weights (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ants in the Food Web (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Ants in the White Mountains, New Hampshire-Notes (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Aphaenogaster (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Aphaenogaster-Rudis Complex (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Aquadro, Charles F.-Evolutionary Biology Faculty at Cornell, October 28, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Australian Sugar Ants (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Australia-Synonymies, etc., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Benjamin Constant Notes (2 Books)-San Miguel de Tucumen and Excursions, Jan.-Feb., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Bibliographies, etc., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Book-Ants and Ant-Plants (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Canada Department of Agriculture-Culture Collections, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Carpenter Ants-New England (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Cerepachyini-Post-1975 Data (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Char. Displ., C-P and Other Data (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Chromosome Negatives-Notebook #2, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Chromosomes -Photos, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Copy of Some Pages from MC2 Type Book (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - R. H. Crozier (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Cytogenetics (Animal) 419 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Dacetini-Generic key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Data Sheets for Karyotypes (blank) (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Dispersal-Dissemination (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - "Division of Labor in Ants"-By William L. Brown, Jr. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Ectatommini-Notes (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Epigraphs, Etc. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Evolutionary Papers-Reprints (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Evolution Papers-Coleopterists and Gould (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Exclusion Principle Talk (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Fire Ant (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Foreign Language Pamphlets (2) (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Formica Obscuriventis, gp-Drawings (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Frog Project (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Geology of Cayuga Lake Basin, May, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Gnamtogenys-Data (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - "Gray Manifesto" (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Indo-Australian-Strumigenys (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Indomyrma-SEM Negatives, Dasypyx (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Insect Wing Origin (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - International Taxonic Register-Correspondence, 1963-1971 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Labels (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Lattke Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Leptothorex Silvestrii gp. (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Leptogenys (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Lordomyrma (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Malagasy-Strum. (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Malaysian Ants (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Odontomachus-Anochetus (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Odontomachus-Raw Metrics, Etc. (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Old Word-Strumigenys-Keys-Letter (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Old World-Strumigenys-Galley Proofs (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - O. Monticala V. Formosa Forel (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Origin of Wings (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Panama Ants (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Papers from Desk (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Peronomyrmex-Taylor Figure (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Pheidole-Spp. List (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Pheidole-World Run 3 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Pentastruma Canina (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Platythyreini (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - "The Present: Zoography"-Chapter XXXII: Distribution (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Pocono Environmental Educational Center (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Population Fluctuations in the Tropics, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Predators (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Prints and Bibliography of Ant Systematics (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - "The Problem of Ant-Mimicry in Spiders"-By Joseph A. Beatty, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Punctuated Equilibrium-Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Punctuated Equilibrium-Miscellaneous Articles, 1977-1987 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Raiding Behavior of Gnamptogenys Horni (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Rhytidoponera Purpurea (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - S. Bryanti and S. Ulcerosa (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - S. Paranetes (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - C. Sulcinodis (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Smithistruma Indo Melanesian (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Smithistruma-Supplemental Material-Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Smithsonian institution-Canal Zone Biological Area (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Symposium-"Ants-Models of Evolution", May 4, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Specimen Cards; Questionnaire to Systematic Zoologist (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Strum. Cochlearis (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Strum. Azalanyi and Related Gps-Working Notes (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Strum.-Gunlachi Group-Negatives and Duplicate Prints (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Strum. Hoplites and S. Ferocior-Drawings and Negatives (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Strum. Iridina Sp. Nov. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Srum. Indo-Australian-Measurements, Etc. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Strum. Lewisi Fig.-Signeae Desir.-Photos (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Strum. Yasumatsui (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Strumigenys-Non-tropical-Notes, Data and Rough Body (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Strumigenys-Rough Copy (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Strumigenys Stemonixys-Holotype Drawings (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Studies on Ectatomini (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Subspecies Data (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Subspecies-Race: Re Sociobiology By Edward Wilson, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - System Data Paper-"tramp Distribution Among Dacetine Ants" (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Thesis By Martin Aluja Schunemann, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Tree-Fogging Data-Panama, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Tulip 2-3-S. Yaliopleura Data (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Vespula Chromosomes-Full-Page Prints, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - V. Vulgaris (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Wamuki, N. G. -- #842 Galley Proofs (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Willow Tree Plot (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Series VII. Manuscripts, Notes, Maps, Articles, Reprints, Correspondence, Studies and Data
  - Ants-Synonymic Notes (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Manuscript-Untitled (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Maps (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Maps and Australian Notes (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Meneoponera-Castanea (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Mermithoidae (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Articles-"Punctuated Equilibrium"-Notes-Citations (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Articles-"Punctuated Equilibrium Excused", 1984-1994 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Reprints (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous Observations on Ant Biology (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous Synonymy, Etc. (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Molitor, Arnulf-Personal Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Myrmica Rubia-Ruginodis-Measurements, Etc. (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Myrmecia-Plot and Figures (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Myrmicinae Genera (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Myrmecina and Relatives (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Myrmecina, Acanthomyrmex, Pristomyrmex (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Negatives, March 31, 1982-June 8, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Neotrop. Strum. (Cordovensis Gp.)-Manuscript and Figures Data (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Neotrop. Strum-Data and Rough Manuscript (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - New Small Smithistrama from I-Marea (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Notes-Epoostrama (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Notes-Drawings-Mesostrama (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Notes and Observations (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Notes-References (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Notes-References-Balsam (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Notes and Rough Manuscripts-Strum. Louisianae Gp. (and Some Szalayi Data) (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Notes-Neotropical Dacetino Biology (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Notes to Wilson in Europe, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Pip Darlington-Australian Notes, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Specimen Notes from Collections, 1963-1973 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Yellow Rain-News Articles, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence (A to Z)
  - "A" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1949-1983 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Adis, Joachim, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Agosti, Donat, 1984-1995 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Alexander, Charles P., 1952-1953, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Alexander, Richard D., 1956-1970 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Alpert, Gary, 1976-1978, 1990-1995 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Andersen, Alan N., 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Arnaud, Paul H., Jr., 1973-1979 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Arnett, Ross H., Jr., 1987 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Arnold, George, 1948-1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Arnoldi, K. V., 1968-1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Ashton, David, 1954-1957 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Ataupah, Hendrik, 1973-1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Audubon Magazine, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Ayre, Gordon L., 1956-1971 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - "B" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1950-1993 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Baker, Robert J., 1978-1986 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Ball, George E., 1959-1967, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Balogh, J., 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Baroni-Urbani, Cesare, 1957-1982 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Barr, David W., 1965-1973 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Barr, Thomas C., Jr., 1965-1971, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Barra, J. A., 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Beard, Robert Gordon, 1965-1974 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Beattie, Andrew J., 1974, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Béïque, Réne, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Benson, Robert B., 1949-1956, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Benson, Woodruff W., 1978-1983 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Berg, Rolf, 1962-1969, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Bernard, Francis, 1952-1983 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Besuchet, Claude, 1959-1985, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Betsch, Jean-Marie, 1969-1978 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Bhatkar, Awinash P., 1972-1974, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Bickel, Daniel John, 1977-1986, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Blum, Murray S., 1965-1982 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Bolton, Barry, 1969-1973 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Bolton, Barry, 1974-1983 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Bolton, Barry, 1984-1995 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Borgmeier, Thomas, 1949-1967 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Boucot, Arthur J., 1976-1986 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Boyd, Howard P., 1978-1981 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Brandão, Carlos Roberts F., 1977-1988 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Broadhead, Edward, 1978-1981 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Brothers, Denis J., 1975-1978 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Brough, Elaine J., 1964-1969, 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Brown, Richard L., 1981-1985 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Brunhuber, Barbara S., 1969-1974, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Buren, William F., 1949, 1955-1976 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Burikam, Intawat, 1981-1984 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Burla, Hans, 1955-1962 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Burnham, Laurie, 1979-1987 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Buschinger, Alfred, 1970-1985 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Bush, Guy, 1961-1976 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - "C" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1950-1990 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - California Academy of Sciences, 1982-1987 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Carpenter, Frank M., 1950-1951, 1961-1987 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Carson, Rachel L., 1958-1962 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Carter, William G., 1958-1969 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Cavill, (G. W.) Ken, 1959-1963 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Chapman, James W., 1949-1961 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - China, Scientists from the People's Republic of, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Christiansen, Kenneth, 1952-1965, 1975-1984 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Clark, John, 1948-1951 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Coher, Ed, 1956-1959 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Cole, Arthur C., Jr., 1939-1969 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Collingwood, Cedric A., 1952-1971 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Consani, Mario, 1948-1952 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Conservation Foundation, The, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Cook, Laurence M., 1958-1961 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Cooper, Ken, 1949-1964, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Cover, Stefan, 1975-1984, 1991-1995 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Crabill, Ralph E., 1955-1980 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Creighton, William, 1939-1955, 1973, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Crozier, Ross, 1963-1972 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Crozier, Ross, 1973-1996 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - "D" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1939-1993 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Darling, Donald Chris, 1977-1990 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Darling, F. Fraser, 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Darlington, Phil, 1950-1971, 1979-1984 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Davidson, Diane W., 1973-1992 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Dlussky, G. M., 1966-1974 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, 1956-1962 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Dodson, Edward O., 1958-1960 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Don, A. Warwick, 1965-1979 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Donisthorpe, Horace, 1943-1952 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Downey, John, 1964-1966 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Douglas, Athol, 1951-1961 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - DuBois, Mark B., 1978-1989 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Dybas, Henry S., 1949-1977 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - "E" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1947-1985 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Eberhard, William and Mary Jane, 1970-1987 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Edwards, J. Gordon, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Ehrlich, Paul R., 1957-1958, 1978-1991 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Eisner, Thomas, 1958-1970, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Eisner, Thomas (and Scientific American), 1956 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Eldredge, Niles, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Emerson, Alfred E., 1958-1975 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Ettershank, George, 1962-1977 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Evans, Howard E., 1953-1986 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - "F" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1948-1995 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Fabres, G., 1976-1979 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Fernández, Fernando, 1986-1995 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Ficken, Robert, 1962-1974 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Fischer, Max, 1958-1960, 1973-1981 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Flanagan, Dennis, 1955-1968 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Forbes, James, 1955-1966 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Francoeur, André, 1965-1992 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Franks, Nigel R., 1977-1986, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Freeland, John, 1955-1958 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Freilich, Jerry E., 1979-1994 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Frost, S. W., 1948-1952, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Furth, David G., 1973-1978, 1991-1993 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - "G" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1956-1996 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Garling, Lyn, 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Gateway, Inc., 1991 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Ghent, Ralph L., 1961-1964 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - Gibson, Roberta Lynn, 1982-1986 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Gillham, Nick W., 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Given, Bruce B., 1951-1958 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - Goñi, Beatriz, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Gotwald, William H., Jr., 1964-1988 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Grant, Peter R., 1972-1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Gray, Barry, 1963-1966 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Greaves, Tom, 1951-1957, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Greenslade, P. J. M., 1964-1968, 1975-1979 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Gregg, Robert E., 1949-1963, 1973-1982 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Gressitt, J. Linsley, 1952-1962, 1971-1981 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Grimaldi, David, 1985-1991 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Gross, Gordon F., 1950-1954, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Guiglia, Delfa, 1950-1974 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Gurney, Ashley B., 1958-1960 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - "H" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1949-1996 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Hamton, Robert J., 1966-1996 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Handel, Steven, 1974-1985 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Haskins, Caryl P., 1947-1985 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Hauschteck, Elisabeth, 1962-1975 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Hazlett, Donald L., 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Herbers, Joan M., 1984 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Hermann, Henry R., Jr., 1965-1975 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Highton, Richard, 1963-1967 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Hinton, Howard E., 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Hocking, B., 1960-1965 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Holland, George P., 1959-1960, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Hölldobler, Bert, 1970, 1979-1991 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Holloway, Beverly A., 1958, 1977-1981 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Howden, H. F., 1968-1982 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Hung, Akey Chang-Fu, 1960-1979 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Hunt, James H., 1955, 1973-1975, 1986-1990 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Hurd, Paul D., 1955-1970 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - "I" and "J" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1958-1991 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Imai, Hirotami, 1964-1974, 1981-1986 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Jackson, Dorothy, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Jaffe, Klaus, 1983-1989 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Janzen, Daniel H., 1961-1975 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Jeanne, Robert, 1970-1981 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Johnson, Clifford, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Johnson, Norman, 1976-1986 (Box 12, Folder 39)